inventing math is no joke and there is a
difference between being told why
something's true and actually generating
it from scratch but at all points I want
you to think to yourself if you were an
early mathematician pondering these
ideas and drawing out the right diagrams
does it feel reasonable that you could
have stumbled across these truths
yourself in this initial video I want to
show how you might stumble into the core
ideas of calculus by thinking very
deeply about one specific bit of
geometry the area of a circle maybe you
know that this is pi * radius squ but
why is there a nice way to think about
where this formula comes from well
contemplating this problem and leaving
yourself open to exploring the
interesting thoughts that come about can
actually lead you to a glimpse of three
big ideas in calculus integrals
derivatives and the fact that they're
opposites